<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Society on Home</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/tags/society/</link><description>Recent content in Society on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 17:56:07 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/tags/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do All It Y</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/20/do-all-it-y/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 17:56:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/20/do-all-it-y/</guid><description>&lt;p>The dualistic nature of things, that appears so often on earth (look for them you will see)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could be based on the polarizing energies of male and female that manifest across mammals and other species.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you think the universe cares about good and evil for example? A very popular duality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire with Fire</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/06/fire-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/06/fire-with-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>Context: American White House Takeover by Protesters (aka racist terrorists)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you ever notice that whenever humanity gets squeezed, our worst selves make the most noise?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The mental-emotional state of the human condition, acting like a virus. And we indirectly like to think we are a part of something.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Opinion Wall</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/01/opinion-wall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/01/opinion-wall/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Opinions are also like onions. They can make others cry, or your &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; when it gets all wrapped in as who you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Given the atomic bomb of the &amp;ldquo;pill&amp;rdquo;, I think professional sex workers deserve some rights. Its not that I want to use their service, but it just does not make sense to control peoples bodies when we send people to war. What we do need to control is health. I do not trust, Dating Apps, Pimps or the Porn industry to regulate health. I would rather Health Canada to step in for safety and cleanliness.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>