<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/</link><description>Recent content on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:03:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A New Earth</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/a-new-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/a-new-earth/</guid><description/></item><item><title>eBPF</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/ebpf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/ebpf/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Progressive Web Apps / Assembly / Sockets</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/webapps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/webapps/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Swamplands of the Soul</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/swamplands/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/swamplands/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tech</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech-item/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech-item/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blockchain</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/blockchain/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Books</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books-item/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books-item/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Linux Namespaces</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/namespaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/namespaces/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mediations - Marcus Aurelius</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/meditations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/meditations/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Selfhosted and IaaS</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/selfhosted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/selfhosted/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Pragmatic Programmer</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/pragmatic_programmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/pragmatic_programmer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security Keys</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/keybase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/keybase/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tao Te Ching</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/tao-te-ting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/tao-te-ting/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Artificial Intelligence / Machine Learning</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/ai-ml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/ai-ml/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Linux Phones</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/linux-phones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/linux-phones/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Cathedral &amp; the Bazaar</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/cathedral_bazaar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/cathedral_bazaar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Scouter Demo</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/scouter-demo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:03:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/scouter-demo/</guid><description>This is a demo for Scouter - a mobile version of &amp;ldquo;I spy with my little eye&amp;rdquo;.
How it Works You can read the full spec doc, but the gist of it is:
turn based game take a picture of something scan it using machine learning for clues another player takes a picture to guess based on clues get points for guessing right Clues Clues include:</description></item><item><title>Sandbox Demo</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/sandcastle-util-demo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:09:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/sandcastle-util-demo/</guid><description>A utility from Micrantha for creating reusable isolated development environments.
This is basically an easy to use abstraction around docker with some extra perks.
file synchronization that follows symlinks keep package manager and system dependencies isolated from host reusable state that can also be persisted as a &amp;lsquo;sandcastle&amp;rsquo; for other sandboxes consistent user file permissions with the host better time tracking with taskwarrior timewarrior scripts write it how I would want it (did not like other tools) {{ }} If you have mastered [mouseless programming](https://themouseless.</description></item><item><title>The Mask of Kara</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/the-mask-of-kara/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:37:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/the-mask-of-kara/</guid><description> Part One: Paranoid Android Gets directed So no thing is affected With a hemaroid Named Floyd And a bowl of debt Full of regret Is that hope I hear? Or denial I fear I love them all But all never enough To be the porridge Of my dreams The flower turns It's shame invisible In a show of pain For someone else To mend the shell Of the lord of flies It is easy to focus As they cloak us On just one word That is never heard She only has one idea in mind You are going to lose Like you deserve Because most of the world Is better than that still You will get used to it With a dummy you can't stand Instead of the death of false Coming from both As if somehow the oath Of rejection Will make them safe again Safe again Without men From the fear of loss Or being without a toss Or their connection To their fiction Of the strands of time That cost a dime Part Two: Look for John without bucks Son For the Mask of Kara Is in your eye And you have no one Left to help It became clear as it has always been year after year There is no win with an empty friend only more sin and no way to end Some losses are too great For society to create Much horror Of an easy adorer But what will become Of the total sum After the sadness Does not turn to gladness When she says farewell After a lengthy affair Loud will sound the bell For your fair share It matches your guests In a suit that earns you The greatest of jests In such an evil rue To burn your tree Into the ground Ignored is your plea Joy is never found Part Three: It is not me He cried internally To keep the flow Of letting go Which was only a sign To the keepers of know He was not benign and could not mow If only he had fought It might have bought His ascension Into another dimension At first, it seemed To be too mean And confusing The misusing losing Which only brought Nothing he sought Into a lost decade His soul decayed They still live In their ignorant fun His mind will sour To their attempts at power</description></item><item><title>Eye Division</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/eye-division/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/eye-division/</guid><description>I see the misery division
Expecting a sense of urgency
Reinforcing weaknesses
With opposite strengths
Wanting their tit for a tat
Sharing the pain
For a missing floor
And make believe ceiling
I see a joy division
Avoiding damages done</description></item><item><title>Man-in-the-Middle</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 11:18:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitm/</guid><description>A man-in-the-middle (MITM) attack is a network security attack where a malicious device enters a network and intercepts traffic between nodes or components.
To accomplish access to a network an attacker needs an entry point.
There are many ways for a malicious device to accomplish access into a network.</description></item><item><title>Alternate Keyboard</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/alternate-keyboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:08:38 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/alternate-keyboard/</guid><description>Decided to switch to using a alternate keyboard layout, not too long ago&amp;hellip;. Well I guess it has been a couple of years now. But I love it.
Always heard about others using the Dvorak keyboard layout and thought, &amp;ldquo;boy that is really neat, but too much work to change&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Old Demos</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/old-demos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/old-demos/</guid><description>Found an old demo of an App from 2010.
Brings back fond memories of hacking away to The Resistance by Muse.
You can still get an updated version on the app store.</description></item><item><title>modd: daemon for reloading</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/modd-live-coding/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 14:46:43 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/modd-live-coding/</guid><description>One of my favourite tools now is modd.
Why is it so great? It does one job, and it does it well, in proper unix fashion.
Monitoring a file-system and running a daemon that reloads if anything changes.
Also in proper Unix fashion, the daemon is sent a configurable SIGHUP when a file changes.</description></item><item><title>When Things Go Wrong</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/when-things-go-wrong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/when-things-go-wrong/</guid><description>I watch them beat you,
Watch them beat you down.
There is nothing I can do,
Brother, just like you.
So when things go wrong,
Go wrong with you,
It hurts me too.
They say you know,
You know what to do.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Mesh Networks</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/blockchain-mesh-internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/blockchain-mesh-internet/</guid><description>Using the blockchain mesh network routers allow freedom and payments.
The underlying core of bitcoin, the blockchain is a system that can be applied to a variety of uses.
One particular disruptive use, that is not mentioned on the wiki, is mesh networks.</description></item><item><title>Git Notes Storage</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/git-notes-as-version-tool-storage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/git-notes-as-version-tool-storage/</guid><description>Am working on a project build tool to make repeatable tasks for Micrantha projects easier.
A module of this tool is automatic versioning using semantic version.
The versioning The way I wanted the versioning to work is to have thresholds for when a version component auto-increments.</description></item><item><title>Audit</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 22:14:09 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/audit/</guid><description>Have removed some incomplete content that was incomplete or did not make sense anymore.
The URL&amp;rsquo;s are now aliased here for reference.</description></item><item><title>Mirroring git with jenkins</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/jenkins-git-mirror/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/jenkins-git-mirror/</guid><description>Introduction For some software development projects, there may be a need to backup or mirror the repository to a different location.
Jenkins or other continuous integration (CI) can automate this. This log is a brief summary of how in case I need to reproduce.</description></item><item><title>Favourite 'nixisms</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/favourite-nixisms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/favourite-nixisms/</guid><description>Introduction A log to myself of things I like about Unix type systems. In case I forget why someday.
Dotfiles files in braille? are they for the blind?Dotfiles in Linux are hidden files preceded with a period. Depending on the program, they are used for configuration in your home directory.</description></item><item><title>Mitmproxy and Android</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitmproxy-and-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitmproxy-and-android/</guid><description>Introduction Debugging network traffic for your app can be useful, and sometimes necessary if the data is not what is expected or inconsistent.
The Proxy I prefer the open source proxy [mitmproxy](https://mitmproxy.org =300x203). Easy to install on OSX with homebrew.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Docker Registry with Dokku</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/deploy-docker-registry-in-dokku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/deploy-docker-registry-in-dokku/</guid><description>Prerequisites You&amp;rsquo;ll need to prepare a bit.
A local path on the server to store registry data. For example: /mydir/registry Docker installed on the client and server machine Dokku installed on the server For Authentication httpasswd command is installed For an External Registry Dokku letsencrypt plugin installed A working domain name pointing to the dokku app.</description></item><item><title>Fortunes on Slack</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/fortunes-microservice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/fortunes-microservice/</guid><description>view the service homepage
Introduction Have always enjoyed the UNIX fortunes program, ever since I was a wee newbie. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it (sad), yes, its like a fortune cookie.
It can be more technical in nature but not always.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Dev Stack on macOS</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/microsoft-dev-stack-macos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/microsoft-dev-stack-macos/</guid><description>Gonna evangelize a little bit.
When Microsoft bought Xamarin, they did not underestimate the power of Xamarin.Forms for building cross platform UIs. Now with the release of Visual Studio for macOS and the Dotnet Core, its looks like its going to stay alive.</description></item><item><title>Hugo + Dokku + Wercker = Goodness</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/hugo-dokku-wercker-goodness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/hugo-dokku-wercker-goodness/</guid><description>Hugo Hugo is a static site generator with many powerful features like archtypes, themes, customization, etc.
Combined with tools like bower and brunch it makes for a pretty powerful app that could be more than a blog.
The workflow is simple - build your assets with brunch, run the hugo generator.</description></item><item><title>c hacking: polymorphing 2</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-hacking-polymoriphing-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-hacking-polymoriphing-2/</guid><description>While working on cparse I found another nifty way to sort of simulate polymorphism.
cparse Another exercise in futility, a C implementation for the REST api at parse.com. Really the core of it is a web client and an object structure using json.</description></item><item><title>Elixir and Phoenix</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/elixir-and-phoenix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/elixir-and-phoenix/</guid><description>Introduction If you dont know phoenix framework, I&amp;rsquo;d describe it as rails for elixir. If you dont know Elixir I&amp;rsquo;d describe it as a functional language that feels like ruby for erlang.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know erlang it has been around a while (open-sourced in 1998) and the virtual machine is designed to be highly fault tolerant and scalable for use in telecoms, banking and instant messaging (WhatsApp).</description></item><item><title>Poor Man's Polymorphism</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/poor-man-s-polymorphism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/poor-man-s-polymorphism/</guid><description>Found out that C structs can be casted between each other if the field types and ordering are the same. It is not portable code, but you can start too see how and why the virtual table and object oriented programming evolved in c++.</description></item><item><title>Crafting a Game With CraftyJS</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</guid><description>Introduction Briefly going to mention a javascript game engine called CraftyJS that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the past couple of days.
Has the usual suspects like Entity Component System, Collision, Sprite Maps, etc.
The Project
Amos the Alien is a small demo I made.</description></item><item><title>C Sqlite Tricks</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-sqlite-tricks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-sqlite-tricks/</guid><description>Introduction Thought I would share some tricks I use for easy data CRUD&amp;rsquo;s in C. I&amp;rsquo;m using Sqlite here, but could apply to any database.
Not saying its the best approach at all (nor ryjen/db), this is just how it evolved for me.</description></item><item><title>Best Programming Quotes</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/best-programming-quotes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/best-programming-quotes/</guid><description>Quotes that relate to software engineering always humble me with their laser-like honesty. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep a collection of my favorites here (in no particular order).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/scouter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/scouter/</guid><description>Scouter Alternatively Eye Spy, iSpy, PicPatrol, CamAgent.
Motivations Mostly to use machine learning and potentially build or strengthen an image classification model.
It is based on the classic game of &amp;ldquo;I Spy&amp;rdquo; and a good way to discover new things about your environment.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/about/</guid><description>Robert Ryan Jennings
@ryjen
A multipotentialite residing in Vancouver area Has an orange tabby cat named Gerty (Gertrude) Enjoys making music (guitar, bass, jazz blues) Loves tech, follows the singularity Reads a lot of psychology and spirituality Plays hockey, hikes, bike rides and kayaks Gertrude "</description></item><item><title>Cracking the Coding Interview</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/cracking-code-interview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/cracking-code-interview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cross Platform Mobile Frameworks</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/mobile-xpf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/mobile-xpf/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Doodles</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/doodles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/doodles/</guid><description>Gerty: A Portrait Stardum: Moon Eating Dinosaurus, Rock, Sex Transfusion Droid, Card, Watercolour Greek Upside Down Smile Pi Penelopy: A Rough Trade Clouds, Card, Watercolour Brain Casing, Cracked Freedom of Self Baggage Joker and the Thief Can, but Nada Life for Breakfast Treble Clef: Art in itself Sabateur Happiness in Apocolypse</description></item><item><title>Fuzz Testing</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/fuzz-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/fuzz-testing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Illusions: Adventures of a Reluctant Messiah</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/illusions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/illusions/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interplanetary File System</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/interplanetary-fs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/interplanetary-fs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Music</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/music/</guid><description>SoundCloud Videos Blues Take 13 is a video to show how a bit of theory and jazz can improve over the standard 12-bar.
Sheet Music Musescore has some nursery rhymes and xmas carols I re-wrote in minor.</description></item><item><title>Phoenix Framework and Elixir/Erlang</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/elixer-erlang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/elixer-erlang/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Poems</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems-item/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems-item/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reactive Extensions</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/reactivex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/reactivex/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reactive Extensions</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/reativext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/reativext/</guid><description/></item><item><title>resume</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/resume/</guid><description>Expertise React Native Redux Android Development iOS Development Clean Architecture JavaScript Java / Kotlin Obj-C / Swift SQL / JSON Git / JIRA HTML5 / CSS3 Python C# / .NET Shell Scripting GoLang Design Patterns Testing Automation Security C / C++ MVVM / MVC / MVP OOP / SOLID Education Diploma in Computer Systems</description></item><item><title>Skystone / A Dream of Eagles</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/skystone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/books/skystone/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SRE / DevOps</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/devops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/devops/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summary</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/summary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/summary/</guid><description>Summary of Ryan Jennings Career History, Expertise and Interests Interests Ryan has a strong interest in cross-platform mobile development from his experience in PALM, Windows Phone, Blackberry, iOS, Android, Xamarin and React-Native. He has good knowledge of UX principles and is particularity strong at bridging native platform solutions to cross-platform user interfaces.</description></item><item><title>ThinkPads</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/thinkpad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/tech/thinkpad/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>