<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Home</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/musings/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 17:56:07 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do All It Y</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/20/do-all-it-y/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 17:56:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/20/do-all-it-y/</guid><description>The dualistic nature of things, that appears so often on earth (look for them you will see)
Could be based on the polarizing energies of male and female that manifest across mammals and other species.
Do you think the universe cares about good and evil for example?</description></item><item><title>Covuck. Pleasantly.</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/07/covuck.-pleasantly./</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/07/covuck.-pleasantly./</guid><description>Aside from being allowed to have no life or interact with people (which is great btw).
Something really positive about covid-19&amp;hellip;
Is something that drives me wild with love 😍 and passion 😘
I am talking about the little extra plumpness to Canadians.</description></item><item><title>Fire with Fire</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/06/fire-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/06/fire-with-fire/</guid><description>Do you ever notice that whenever humanity gets squeezed, our worst selves make the most noise?
The mental-emotional state of the human condition, acting like a virus. And we indirectly like to think we are a part of something.
All the pandemic, racism, sexism, and inequality is hugely symptomatic of suffering and the mind run amok in resistance.</description></item><item><title>Who are you?</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/06/who-are-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/06/who-are-you/</guid><description>Who are you? Who am I?
Are you a body?
Are you a thought?
Are you more than a pin point in time?
If your body degenerates, are you still your body?
If your thought changes, are you still your thought?</description></item><item><title>Opinion Wall</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/01/opinion-wall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2021/01/01/opinion-wall/</guid><description>Opinions are also like onions. They can make others cry, or your &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; when it gets all wrapped in as who you are.
Given the atomic bomb of the &amp;ldquo;pill&amp;rdquo;, I think professional sex workers deserve some rights.</description></item><item><title>Questioning the Queue</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/12/15/questioning-the-queue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/12/15/questioning-the-queue/</guid><description>Do you feel entitled to be a victim of someone or something else?
Do you think your mind or the situation generates more suffering?
Do you think that you deserve better? That you are overlooked?
That your perception of reality is absolute?</description></item><item><title>Mornin 'Mericas.</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/21/mornin-mericas./</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/21/mornin-mericas./</guid><description>Winners and Losers. All of us have probably felt this is true in some level.
Its true with men, and the various games in the lives of the different hues of man.
Have not read Trumpian literature on the subject but do have my own opinion that is somewhat biased to the loser side.</description></item><item><title>Covac</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/09/covac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/09/covac/</guid><description>Am very glad a covid vaccine has a real chance.
&amp;ldquo;Little bottle of hope&amp;rdquo; for saving humans and creating prosperity for more (groan, yes, more humans are needed now eh).
That being said, I am actually very bitter going back to the new-normal, with a lot of skepticism.</description></item><item><title>The Dreams</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/31/the-dreams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/31/the-dreams/</guid><description>Life is a like a dream, a background awareness of reality.…. as a nightmare at worst and a delusion at best. You can guide your self down the stream, but you do not know where you are going and you cannot go back.</description></item><item><title>Poly Techs</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/18/poly-techs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/18/poly-techs/</guid><description>Politics. Does it matter? Why?
It is great that the human condition is suffering, as there is a plethora of issues to take unconscious action on.
When it comes down to actionable issues that are most common, it is always children.</description></item><item><title>The Dead Triplets</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/09/05/the-dead-triplets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/09/05/the-dead-triplets/</guid><description>This post could about music theory and rhythm, such as the triplet guitar riffs in invincible&amp;hellip;
But this about a single chapter, in a single book from the swamp. It is probably already a more influential book than I realize, from which I quote liberally and implicitly.</description></item><item><title>Myths Fading, Direction of Evolution</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/07/07/myths-fading-direction-of-evolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/07/07/myths-fading-direction-of-evolution/</guid><description>Remembering a concept from the book Sapiens (paraphrasing):
Ape hierarchy only existed in small groups with a limit (150 or so) with a dominant leader (alpha). This applies to humans as well, but we were able so surpass the threshold with myths and better communication.</description></item><item><title>12 Bar Blues</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/10/02/12-bar-blues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/10/02/12-bar-blues/</guid><description>You might have heard of the blues, made famous as a way to make a living in the US for marginalized citizens.
The story goes that the French taught the Black community music theory and unlocked a creative juice thirsting for expression.</description></item><item><title>What I've Learned from 4 Years of Eckhart Tolle</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</guid><description>Major Lessons Eckhart Tolle or ET is a unique individual, author and orator. After a suicidal night where he thought &amp;ldquo;I cannot live with myself any longer&amp;rdquo; and recognized the oddity of thought, as if there were two people &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;myself&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>