<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Poems on Home</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/</link><description>Recent content in Poems on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:37:41 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mask of Kara</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/the-mask-of-kara/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:37:41 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/the-mask-of-kara/</guid><description> Part One: Paranoid Android Gets directed So no thing is affected With a hemaroid Named Floyd And a bowl of debt Full of regret Is that hope I hear? Or denial I fear I love them all But all never enough To be the porridge Of my dreams The flower turns It&amp;#39;s shame invisible In a show of pain For someone else To mend the shell Of the lord of flies It is easy to focus As they cloak us On just one word That is never heard She only has one idea in mind You are going to lose Like you deserve Because most of the world Is better than that still You will get used to it With a dummy you can&amp;#39;t stand Instead of the death of false Coming from both As if somehow the oath Of rejection Will make them safe again Safe again Without men From the fear of loss Or being without a toss Or their connection To their fiction Of the strands of time That cost a dime Part Two: Look for John without bucks Son For the Mask of Kara Is in your eye And you have no one Left to help It became clear as it has always been year after year There is no win with an empty friend only more sin and no way to end Some losses are too great For society to create Much horror Of an easy adorer But what will become Of the total sum After the sadness Does not turn to gladness When she says farewell After a lengthy affair Loud will sound the bell For your fair share It matches your guests In a suit that earns you The greatest of jests In such an evil rue To burn your tree Into the ground Ignored is your plea Joy is never found Part Three: It is not me He cried internally To keep the flow Of letting go Which was only a sign To the keepers of know He was not benign and could not mow If only he had fought It might have bought His ascension Into another dimension At first, it seemed To be too mean And confusing The misusing losing Which only brought Nothing he sought Into a lost decade His soul decayed They still live In their ignorant fun His mind will sour To their attempts at power</description></item><item><title>Eye Division</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/eye-division/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 09:03:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/eye-division/</guid><description>I see the misery division
Expecting a sense of urgency
Reinforcing weaknesses
With opposite strengths
Wanting their tit for a tat
Sharing the pain
For a missing floor
And make believe ceiling
I see a joy division
Avoiding damages done</description></item><item><title>When Things Go Wrong</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/when-things-go-wrong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/art/poems/when-things-go-wrong/</guid><description>I watch them beat you,
Watch them beat you down.
There is nothing I can do,
Brother, just like you.
So when things go wrong,
Go wrong with you,
It hurts me too.
They say you know,
You know what to do.</description></item></channel></rss>