<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ryan jennings</title>
    <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ryan jennings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>schemaless databases</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/08/03/schemaless-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/08/03/schemaless-databases/</guid>
      <description>Schemaless databases came into my radar with MongoDB, Redis and such. I have often admired the ability to alter schema on fly.
Solutions like the now defunct cparse, couchbase and Firebase have been big successes.
The success of schemaless databases makes a lot of sense in part because of API consumption and mobile devices if you can get the synchronization part right.
At a startup I worked at for a few years, I experimented with a hybrid relational database and schemaless using JSON extensions for SQLite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myths Fading, Direction of Evolution</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/07/07/myths-fading-direction-of-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/07/07/myths-fading-direction-of-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Remembering a concept from the book Sapiens (paraphrasing):
 Ape hierarchy only existed in small groups with a limit (150 or so) with a dominant leader (alpha). This applies to humans as well, but we were able so surpass the threshold with myths and better communication.
 And the definition of ego by ET 👽:
 A complete and total identification with form as who you are - a thought form or a physical form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git notes as a storage mechanism</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/06/25/git-notes-as-a-storage-mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/06/25/git-notes-as-a-storage-mechanism/</guid>
      <description>Am working on a project build tool to make repeatable tasks for Micrantha projects easier.
A module of this tool is automatic versioning using semantic version.
The versioning The way I wanted the versioning to work is to have thresholds for when a version component auto-increments.
For example:
 A patch version will increment after 300 builds A minor version will increment after 100 patch builds  This is a potential feature that projects can use as a reminder to bump a version if there are breaking changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Bar Blues</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/10/02/12-bar-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/10/02/12-bar-blues/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard of the blues, made famous as a way to make a living in the US for marginalized citizens.
The story goes that the French taught the Black community music theory and unlocked a creative juice thirsting for expression.
12 bar blues is very basic music lesson and is known universally by musicians as a way to quickly join other musicians musically.
Scales: a quick primer 🎼 The most common western scale - the major scale - has 7 notes representing pitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirroring git with jenkins</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/07/05/mirroring-git-with-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/07/05/mirroring-git-with-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For some software development projects, there may be a need to backup or mirror the repository to a different location.
Jenkins or other continuous integration (CI) can automate this. This log is a brief summary of how in case I need to reproduce.
Workflow The requirement is to have a single jenkins job that synchronizes various other projects and repositories.
To do this, the job calls another job to mirror any source repository to any set of destination repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A self hosting journey</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/02/07/a-self-hosting-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/02/07/a-self-hosting-journey/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Would like to say that I have valid privacy or security concerns. Or because it can be done better. But the reality is, I just want to self host because I can.
Where to start? The awesome self hosted page lists just about every cloud service I use with a replaceable near-quality solution, if your willing to sacrifice a bit for it.
The other appealing factor is that most of the solutions can be containerized and reproducible across servers - meaning more availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Learned from 4 Years of Eckhart Tolle</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</guid>
      <description>Major Lessons Eckhart Tolle or ET is a unique individual, author and orator. After a suicidal night where he thought &amp;ldquo;I cannot live with myself any longer&amp;rdquo; and recognized the oddity of thought, as if there were two people &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;myself&amp;rdquo;. That recognition brought a radical inner transformation and years of intense bliss. He later learned more about what happened to him and became a &amp;ldquo;spiritual teacher&amp;rdquo;.
His books The Power of Now and A New Earth have been #1 on the New York Times best seller list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favourite &#39;nixisms</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/11/05/favourite-nixisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/11/05/favourite-nixisms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A log to myself of things I like about Unix type systems. In case I forget why someday.
Dotfiles files in braille? are they for the blind?Dotfiles in Linux are hidden files preceded with a period. Depending on the program, they are used for configuration in your home directory.
It is common to have a set of dotfiles that you use regularly on different computer systems.
There are many ways and tools to manage your dotfiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitmproxy and Android</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/05/16/mitmproxy-and-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/05/16/mitmproxy-and-android/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Debugging network traffic for your app can be useful, and sometimes necessary if the data is not what is expected or inconsistent.
The Proxy I prefer the open source proxy [mitmproxy](https://mitmproxy.org =300x203). Easy to install on OSX with homebrew.
brew install mitmproxy
I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it up to you to explore its greatness, I just wanna clarify the android setup.
Steps 1) mitmproxy Choose a port (ex. 8888) and start the program: mitmproxy -p 8888:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Docker Registry with Dokku</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/02/19/deploy-docker-registry-with-dokku/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/02/19/deploy-docker-registry-with-dokku/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites You&amp;rsquo;ll need to prepare a bit.
  A local path on the server to store registry data. For example: /mydir/registry Docker installed on the client and server machine Dokku installed on the server  For Authentication  httpasswd command is installed  For an External Registry  Dokku letsencrypt plugin installed A working domain name pointing to the dokku app. For example, https://registry.mydomain.com  Create the dokku app Create the dokku app and retag a pre-existing repository image to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortunes on Slack</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/01/22/fortunes-on-slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2018/01/22/fortunes-on-slack/</guid>
      <description>view the service homepage
Introduction Have always enjoyed the UNIX fortunes program, ever since I was a wee newbie. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it (sad), yes, its like a fortune cookie.
It can be more technical in nature but not always. It also has poems, quotations, and if enabled - offensive content.
Often I would find a fortune I&amp;rsquo;d like to share and pipe it to a snippet from the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Stack on macOS</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>Gonna evangelize a little bit.
When Microsoft bought Xamarin, they did not underestimate the power of Xamarin.Forms for building cross platform UIs. Now with the release of Visual Studio for macOS and the Dotnet Core, its looks like its going to stay alive.
Development Environment  macOS, XCode Android SDK Dotnet core Visual Studio for macOS nuget  Web ASP.NET Production Environment  Digital Ocean Dotnet core on Docker Dokku, docker based heroku  Platforms Targeted in One Solution  iOS Android Web ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir and Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2015/09/09/elixir-and-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2015/09/09/elixir-and-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you dont know phoenix framework, I&amp;rsquo;d describe it as rails for elixir. If you dont know Elixir I&amp;rsquo;d describe it as a functional language that feels like ruby for erlang.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know erlang it has been around a while (open-sourced in 1998) and the virtual machine is designed to be highly fault tolerant and scalable for use in telecoms, banking and instant messaging (WhatsApp).
Experimenting To exercise the framework, I created yet another chat app (I know, I know).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Found out that C structs can be casted between each other if the field types and ordering are the same. It is not portable code, but you can start too see how and why the virtual table and object oriented programming evolved in c++.
As far as I know it would still be possible to write this in c++, but as always, you should definitely not.
A Quick Example struct Animal { int eyes; } struct Dog { int eyes; /* dog specific */ int tail; } struct Human{ int eyes; /* human specific */ int brain; } Passing humans or dogs to any function that takes an animal with a cast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a Game With CraftyJS</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/11/17/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/11/17/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Briefly going to mention a javascript game engine called CraftyJS that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the past couple of days.
Has the usual suspects like Entity Component System, Collision, Sprite Maps, etc.
The Project 
Amos the Alien is a small demo I made.
I knew that I wanted a scrolling background of some sort - in other words - parallax scrolling. I also knew that I wanted two modes of scrolling: A) automatic background scrollin (clouds, etc) and character movement scrolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Sqlite Tricks</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thought I would share some tricks I use for easy data CRUD&amp;rsquo;s in C. I&amp;rsquo;m using Sqlite here, but could apply to any database.
Not saying its the best approach at all (nor ryjen/db), this is just how it evolved for me.
Mapping The core of my data access is the FieldMap structure, which determines how to save each field to the database.
/* * this is the magical table used to communicate between memory and the database */ typedef struct FieldMap { const char *name; /* name of the field */ void *value; /* a pointer to the value of the field */ int type; /* type of value */ const void *arg1; /* additional argument */ const void *arg2; /* additional argument */ int flags; /* usage flags */ } FieldMap; /* callback for custom field types */ typedef int (*CustomField) (sqlite3_stmt *, int column, FieldMap *field); typedef void (*DbCallback) (sqlite3_stmt *); Basically you would have to:Example 1 - Saving This high level example shows building a quick table for each field we want to save in the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Programming Quotes</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/04/10/best-programming-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2012/04/10/best-programming-quotes/</guid>
      <description>Quotes that relate to software engineering always humble me with their laser-like honesty. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep a collection of my favorites here (in no particular order).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/things/</guid>
      <description>Tech Cross Platform Mobile Frameworks React Native, Flutter and Xamarin are most interesting to me. It is a hard task to create the holy grail framework across products you have no control over, but they seem to do it pretty well.  Blockchain A secure decentralized tech for alt-currency tech, its quite amazing what netgineers have done with it. Notably cryptokitties and for music artists Ujo.
 Interplanetary File System Peer-to-peer for the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doodles</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/doodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/doodles/</guid>
      <description>  ᐊ                                ᐅ  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/music/</guid>
      <description>SoundCloud  Videos  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/resume/</guid>
      <description>An online software enthusiast since 1999, educated in computer systems from BCIT part time, experienced in the industry since 2007. Passionate about solving problems, elegant simple code and learning. Mobile focused career and very well rounded technologist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>