<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on coda.life</title>
    <link>https://coda.life/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on coda.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://coda.life/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Stack on macOS</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>Gonna evangelize a little bit.
When Microsoft bought Xamarin, they did not underestimate the power of Xamarin.Forms for building cross platform UIs. Now with the release of Visual Studio for macOS and the Dotnet Core, its looks like its going to stay alive.
Development Environment  macOS, XCode Android SDK Dotnet core Visual Studio for macOS nuget  Web ASP.NET Production Environment  Digital Ocean Dotnet core on Docker Dokku, docker based heroku  Platforms Targeted in One Solution  iOS Android Web ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Just when you think you know everything about C&amp;hellip; a way to polymorph C data structures.
How? Structs with the same field types and ordering can be casted.
This is an attempt at an example.
Note: Don&#39;t do anything like this in the real world.  Example Story Given a base structure called vehicle&amp;hellip;
typedef struct { int key; } Vehicle;  Sub structures must implement the exact types and order to cast it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Sqlite Tricks</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thought I would share some tricks I use for easy data CRUD&amp;rsquo;s in C. I&amp;rsquo;m using Sqlite here, but could apply to any database.
Not saying its the best approach at all (nor ryjen/db), this is just how it evolved for me.
Mapping The core of my data access is the FieldMap structure, which determines how to save each field to the database.
/* * this is the magical table used to communicate between memory and the database */ typedef struct FieldMap { const char *name; /* name of the field */ void *value; /* a pointer to the value of the field */ int type; /* type of value */ const void *arg1; /* additional argument */ const void *arg2; /* additional argument */ int flags; /* usage flags */ } FieldMap; /* callback for custom field types */ typedef int (*CustomField) (sqlite3_stmt *, int column, FieldMap *field); typedef void (*DbCallback) (sqlite3_stmt *);  Note: these examples will create this table dynamically with an object, however this can be used as a static table.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>