<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on coda.life</title>
    <link>https://nullstruct.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on coda.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nullstruct.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Learned from 4 Years of Eckhart Tolle</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</guid>
      <description>Major Lessons Eckhart Tolle is a unique individual who experienced a radical shift in thinking after disassociating with an especially negative fictional self. After learning what happened to him, he became a &amp;ldquo;spiritual teacher&amp;rdquo;, travelling the world writing, helping, and reminding people they can live without their own suffering.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt paraphrasing the major takeaways I&amp;rsquo;ve received after following, reading and watching Eckhart Tolle over the last 4 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favourite &#39;nixisms</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2018/11/05/favourite-nixisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2018/11/05/favourite-nixisms/</guid>
      <description>introduction A log to myself of things I like about Unix type systems. In case I forget why someday.
dotfiles files in braille? are they for the blind?
Dotfiles in Linux are hidden files preceded with a period. Depending on the program, they are used for configuration in your home directory.
It is common to have a set of dotfiles that you use regularly on different computer systems.
There are many ways and tools to manage your dotfiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitmproxy and Android</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2018/05/16/mitmproxy-and-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2018/05/16/mitmproxy-and-android/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Debugging network traffic for your app can be useful, and sometimes necessary if the data is not what is expected or inconsistent.
The Proxy I prefer the open source proxy mitmproxy. Easy to install on OSX with homebrew.
brew install mitmproxy
I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it up to you to explore its greatness, I just wanna clarify the android setup.
Steps 1) mitmproxy Choose a port (ex. 8888) and start the program: mitmproxy -p 8888:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Docker Registry with Dokku</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2018/02/19/deploy-docker-registry-with-dokku/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2018/02/19/deploy-docker-registry-with-dokku/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites You&amp;rsquo;ll need to prepare a bit.
 A local path on the server to store registry data. For example: /mydir/registry Docker installed on the client and server machine Dokku installed on the server  For Authentication  httpasswd command is installed  For an External Registry  Dokku letsencrypt plugin installed A working domain name pointing to the dokku app. For example, https://registry.mydomain.com  Create the dokku app Create the dokku app and retag a pre-existing repository image to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortunes on Slack</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2018/01/22/fortunes-on-slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2018/01/22/fortunes-on-slack/</guid>
      <description>view the service homepage
Introduction Have always enjoyed the UNIX fortunes program, ever since I was a wee newbie. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it (sad), yes, its like a fortune cookie.
It can be more technical in nature but not always. It also has poems, quotations, and if enabled - offensive content.
Often I would find a fortune I&amp;rsquo;d like to share and pipe it to a snippet from the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Stack on macOS</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>Gonna evangelize a little bit.
When Microsoft bought Xamarin, they did not underestimate the power of Xamarin.Forms for building cross platform UIs. Now with the release of Visual Studio for macOS and the Dotnet Core, its looks like its going to stay alive.
Development Environment  macOS, XCode Android SDK Dotnet core Visual Studio for macOS nuget  Web ASP.NET Production Environment  Digital Ocean Dotnet core on Docker Dokku, docker based heroku  Platforms Targeted in One Solution  iOS Android Web ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir and Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2015/09/09/elixir-and-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2015/09/09/elixir-and-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Saw a post on reddit about this new web framework phoenix. It is an elixir based framework. Elixir is based upon erlang. Erlang has been around a while (open-sourced in 1998) and is a massively scalable and highly reliable language used in telecoms, banking and instant messaging (among others).
Elixir brings very ruby-ish syntax to the language. Phoenix framework is like rails for elixir, and is pretty full featured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Just when you think you know everything about C&amp;hellip; a way to polymorph C data structures.
How? Structs with the same field types and ordering can be casted.
This is an attempt at an example.
Note: Don&#39;t do anything like this in the real world.  Example Story Given a base structure called vehicle&amp;hellip;
typedef struct { int key; } Vehicle;  Sub structures must implement the exact types and order to cast it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a Game With CraftyJS</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2012/11/17/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2012/11/17/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Briefly going to mention a javascript game engine called CraftyJS that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the past couple of days.
Has the usual suspects like Entity Component System, Collision, Sprite Maps, etc.
The Project 
Amos the Alien is a small demo I made.
I knew that I wanted a scrolling background of some sort - in other words - parallax scrolling. I also knew that I wanted two modes of scrolling: A) automatic background scrollin (clouds, etc) and character movement scrolling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Sqlite Tricks</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thought I would share some tricks I use for easy data CRUD&amp;rsquo;s in C. I&amp;rsquo;m using Sqlite here, but could apply to any database.
Not saying its the best approach at all (nor ryjen/db), this is just how it evolved for me.
Mapping The core of my data access is the FieldMap structure, which determines how to save each field to the database.
/* * this is the magical table used to communicate between memory and the database */ typedef struct FieldMap { const char *name; /* name of the field */ void *value; /* a pointer to the value of the field */ int type; /* type of value */ const void *arg1; /* additional argument */ const void *arg2; /* additional argument */ int flags; /* usage flags */ } FieldMap; /* callback for custom field types */ typedef int (*CustomField) (sqlite3_stmt *, int column, FieldMap *field); typedef void (*DbCallback) (sqlite3_stmt *);  Note: these examples will create this table dynamically with an object, however this can be used as a static table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Programming Quotes</title>
      <link>https://nullstruct.com/2012/04/10/best-programming-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nullstruct.com/2012/04/10/best-programming-quotes/</guid>
      <description>Sites with programmer quotes that always humble me with their laser-like honesty. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep a collection of my favourites here (in no particular order).
 &amp;ldquo;The only real education is self-education&amp;rdquo; - Aristotle
 If I&amp;rsquo;d known computer science was going to be like this, I&amp;rsquo;d never have given up being a rock &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; roll star. &amp;ndash; G. Hirst
 Lubarsky&amp;rsquo;s Law of Cybernetic Entomology: There&amp;rsquo;s always one more bug</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>