<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Archives on Home</title>
    <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Archives on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Docker Registry with Dokku</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/deploy-docker-registry-in-dokku/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/deploy-docker-registry-in-dokku/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites You&amp;rsquo;ll need to prepare a bit.
  A local path on the server to store registry data. For example: /mydir/registry Docker installed on the client and server machine Dokku installed on the server  For Authentication  httpasswd command is installed  For an External Registry  Dokku letsencrypt plugin installed A working domain name pointing to the dokku app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Stack on macOS</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/microsoft-dev-stack-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/microsoft-dev-stack-macos/</guid>
      <description>Gonna evangelize a little bit.
When Microsoft bought Xamarin, they did not underestimate the power of Xamarin.Forms for building cross platform UIs. Now with the release of Visual Studio for macOS and the Dotnet Core, its looks like its going to stay alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo &#43; Dokku &#43; Wercker = Goodness</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/hugo-dokku-wercker-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/hugo-dokku-wercker-goodness/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Hugo is a static site generator with many powerful features like archtypes, themes, customization, etc.
Combined with tools like bower and brunch it makes for a pretty powerful app that could be more than a blog.
The workflow is simple - build your assets with brunch, run the hugo generator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c hacking: polymorphing 2</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-hacking-polymoriphing-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-hacking-polymoriphing-2/</guid>
      <description>While working on cparse I found another nifty way to sort of simulate polymorphism.
cparse Another exercise in futility, a C implementation for the REST api at parse.com. Really the core of it is a web client and an object structure using json.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gobo / Homebrew and Linux Application Organization</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/gobo-homebrew-and-linux-application-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/gobo-homebrew-and-linux-application-organization/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I really liked the way Gobo Linux re-factored the organization of a linux filesystem.
The short story of Gobo was to have each Recipe (application/library) install everything it needs into its own directory. The app files are then linked to support the legacy filesystem that the OS needs (You can read more at Gobo at Glance or the history of gobo linux).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackberry &#43; Push &#43; Android Hacking</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/blackberry-push-android-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/blackberry-push-android-hack/</guid>
      <description>I would like to track my experience with setting up push messaging for blackberry using an android application.
The main blackberry link on this subject provides some basics, however I will try go into some detail on the process I used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/poor-man-s-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/poor-man-s-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Found out that C structs can be casted between each other if the field types and ordering are the same. It is not portable code, but you can start too see how and why the virtual table and object oriented programming evolved in c++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryan Jennings Day - June 7th</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/ryan-jennings-day-june-7th/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/ryan-jennings-day-june-7th/</guid>
      <description>Today something interesting started on Facebook: Ryan Jennings Day. (Only geniuses named Ryan Jennings could conceive of something this awesome - har har)
Besides putting in vacation time, you can join the facebook group if you wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a Game With CraftyJS</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/crafting-a-game-with-craftyjs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Briefly going to mention a javascript game engine called CraftyJS that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the past couple of days.
Has the usual suspects like Entity Component System, Collision, Sprite Maps, etc.
The Project 
Amos the Alien is a small demo I made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Found Bug in Apple Tool &#39;HeaderDoc&#39;</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/found-bug-in-apple-tool-headerdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/found-bug-in-apple-tool-headerdoc/</guid>
      <description>HeaderDoc is a tool to generate source code documentation for many languages. Recently, I noticed that one of the command line tools &amp;lsquo;gatherheaderdoc&amp;rsquo; was producing a blank output file. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure why at first, but since its just a perl script I delved a little deeper to find the bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Droid Fortunes: An Experiment in Android Widgets</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/droid-fortunes-an-experiment-in-android-widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/droid-fortunes-an-experiment-in-android-widgets/</guid>
      <description>Background I have it set up on my OSX machine to give me a random fortune when I log into the shell. I thought it would be a good idea to port this to Android in the form of a widget and Droid Fortunes was born!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Sqlite Tricks</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-sqlite-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/c-sqlite-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Thought I would share some tricks I use for easy data CRUD&amp;rsquo;s in C. I&amp;rsquo;m using Sqlite here, but could apply to any database.
Not saying its the best approach at all (nor ryjen/db), this is just how it evolved for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>merge folders AppleScript service</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/merge-folders-applescript-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/archive/merge-folders-applescript-service/</guid>
      <description>I recently tried to merge folders in OSX Lion using copy/paste in finder. To my surprise, the only action I could perform was to replace the folder.
I came up with a little AppleScript to create a Finder service for merging folders.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
