<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coda.life</title>
    <link>https://coda.life/</link>
    <description>Recent content on coda.life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; all rights reserved, ryan jennings</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://coda.life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortunes on Slack</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2018/01/22/fortunes-on-slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2018/01/22/fortunes-on-slack/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have always enjoyed the UNIX fortunes program, ever since I was a wee newbie. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it (sad), yes, its like a fortune cookie.
Except that it can be more technical in nature but not always. It also has poems, quotations, and if enabled - offensive content.
Often I will find a fortune, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share, and would simply make a snippet of my terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Dev Stack on macOS</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2016/11/27/microsoft-dev-stack-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>Gonna evangelize a little bit.
When Microsoft bought Xamarin, they did not underestimate the power of Xamarin.Forms for building cross platform UIs. Now with the release of Visual Studio for macOS and the Dotnet Core, its looks like its going to stay alive.
Development Environment  macOS, XCode Android SDK Dotnet core Visual Studio for macOS nuget  Web ASP.NET Production Environment  Digital Ocean Dotnet core on Docker Dokku, docker based heroku  Platforms Targeted in One Solution  iOS Android Web ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir and Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2015/09/09/elixir-and-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2015/09/09/elixir-and-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Saw a post on reddit about this new web framework phoenix. It is an elixir based framework. Elixir is based upon erlang. Erlang has been around a while (open-sourced in 1998) and is a massively scalable and highly reliable language used in telecoms, banking and instant messaging (among others).
Elixir brings very ruby-ish syntax to the language. Phoenix framework is like rails for elixir, and is pretty full featured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Polymorphism</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2012/11/30/poor-mans-polymorphism/</guid>
      <description>Just when you think you know everything about C&amp;hellip; a way to polymorph C data structures.
How? Structs with the same field types and ordering can be casted.
Note: Don&#39;t do anything like this. Not portable or guaranteed that I know of.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Sqlite Tricks</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/2012/05/15/c-sqlite-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Well, I thought I would share some tricks I use for easy data CRUD&amp;rsquo;s in C (potentially C++/ObjC but its lacking typesafety). I&amp;rsquo;m using sqlite here, but could apply to any database.
This is how my data access works - I&amp;rsquo;m not saying its the best approach, its just how its evolved for me.
/* The account table name */ #define ACCOUNT_TABLE &amp;quot;account&amp;quot; /* a structure representing the account fields */ field_map account_values[] = { {&amp;quot;login&amp;quot;, &amp;amp;acc-&amp;gt;login, SQL_TEXT}, {&amp;quot;email&amp;quot;, &amp;amp;acc-&amp;gt;email, SQL_TEXT}, {&amp;quot;password&amp;quot;, &amp;amp;acc-&amp;gt;password, SQL_TEXT}, {&amp;quot;timezone&amp;quot;, &amp;amp;acc-&amp;gt;timezone, SQL_INT}, {0} }; /* saves the fields to the database */ acc-&amp;gt;id = db_save(account_values, ACCOUNT_TABLE, acc-&amp;gt;id);  As you can see, saving a structure is as simple as creating a field_map table and calling db_save.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/things/</guid>
      <description>RxJava for Android Developers If you were confused about Rx or RxJava, this book does a great job of a practical explanation. Its still in early access as of 12/20/17.
 Cracking the Coding Interview Found this book to be very useful, good example problems and content just for your own enjoyment of solving if your not interviewing.
 The Clean Coder Much good advice in here, if your interested in being more professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/music/</guid>
      <description>Videos  SoundCloud  Other View some gear on Equipboard.com
Find canadian musicians on Bandmix.ca</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/about/</guid>
      <description> &amp;nbsp; 778-240-3248  &amp;nbsp; ryan@coda.life  &amp;nbsp; [github.com/ryjen](https://github.com/ryjen?tab=repositories)   &amp;nbsp; [ca.linkedin.com/in/ryjen](http://ca.linkedin.com/in/ryjen)  &amp;nbsp; [coda.life](http://coda.life)  I currently work as a mobile application developer for a respectable software company. If you’d like, you can view my [resume](/about/resume). </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/projects/</guid>
      <description>Open Source Closed Source   prep A c++ package manager and build tool. Think npm for c++. Uses plugins for system independent dependency management and builds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/resume/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/resume/resume/</guid>
      <description>778-240-3248     ryan@coda.life     github.com/ryjen     ca.linkedin.com/in/ryjen    https://coda.life   (Robert) Ryan Jennings  Self-taught programmer since 2002, formally educated in Computer Systems at BCIT with distinction. Started professionally in quality assurance and embedded systems and been a part of the mobile revolution for 8 years on multiple platforms and languages.
 Pragmatism has been a guiding philosophy during education and professional life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>timeline</title>
      <link>https://coda.life/resume/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://coda.life/resume/timeline/</guid>
      <description>2007 - something happened here    2008 - something happened here        2010 - something happened here    2011 - something happened here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>