<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Home</title>
    <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:03:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scouter Demo</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/scouter-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 00:03:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/scouter-demo/</guid>
      <description>This is a demo for Scouter - a mobile version of &amp;ldquo;I spy with my little eye&amp;rdquo;.
 
How it Works You can read the full spec doc, but the gist of it is:
turn based game take a picture of something scan it using machine learning for clues another player takes a picture to guess based on clues get points for guessing right  Clues Clues include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sandbox Demo</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/sandcastle-util-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:09:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/sandcastle-util-demo/</guid>
      <description>A utility from Micrantha for creating reusable isolated development environments.
This is basically an easy to use abstraction around docker with some extra perks.
 file synchronization that follows symlinks keep package manager and system dependencies isolated from host reusable state that can also be persisted as a &amp;lsquo;sandcastle&amp;rsquo; for other sandboxes consistent user file permissions with the host better time tracking with taskwarrior timewarrior scripts write it how I would want it (did not like other tools)  {{ }} If you have mastered [mouseless programming](https://themouseless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man-in-the-Middle</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 11:18:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitm/</guid>
      <description>A man-in-the-middle (MITM) attack is a network security attack where a malicious device enters a network and intercepts traffic between nodes or components.
To accomplish access to a network an attacker needs an entry point.
There are many ways for a malicious device to accomplish access into a network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternate Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/alternate-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:08:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/alternate-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Decided to switch to using a alternate keyboard layout, not too long ago&amp;hellip;. Well I guess it has been a couple of years now. But I love it.
Always heard about others using the Dvorak keyboard layout and thought, &amp;ldquo;boy that is really neat, but too much work to change&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Demos</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/old-demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/old-demos/</guid>
      <description>Found an old demo of an App from 2010.
 Brings back fond memories of hacking away to The Resistance by Muse.
You can still get an updated version on the app store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>modd: daemon for reloading</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/modd-live-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 14:46:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/modd-live-coding/</guid>
      <description>One of my favourite tools now is modd.
Why is it so great? It does one job, and it does it well, in proper unix fashion.
Monitoring a file-system and running a daemon that reloads if anything changes.
Also in proper Unix fashion, the daemon is sent a configurable SIGHUP when a file changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Mesh Networks</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/blockchain-mesh-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/blockchain-mesh-internet/</guid>
      <description>Using the blockchain mesh network routers allow freedom and payments.
The underlying core of bitcoin, the blockchain is a system that can be applied to a variety of uses.
One particular disruptive use, that is not mentioned on the wiki, is mesh networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Notes Storage</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/git-notes-as-version-tool-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/git-notes-as-version-tool-storage/</guid>
      <description>Am working on a project build tool to make repeatable tasks for Micrantha projects easier.
A module of this tool is automatic versioning using semantic version.
The versioning The way I wanted the versioning to work is to have thresholds for when a version component auto-increments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audit</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/audit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 22:14:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/audit/</guid>
      <description>Have removed some incomplete content that was incomplete or did not make sense anymore.
The URL&amp;rsquo;s are now aliased here for reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirroring git with jenkins</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/jenkins-git-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/jenkins-git-mirror/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For some software development projects, there may be a need to backup or mirror the repository to a different location.
Jenkins or other continuous integration (CI) can automate this. This log is a brief summary of how in case I need to reproduce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favourite &#39;nixisms</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/favourite-nixisms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/favourite-nixisms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A log to myself of things I like about Unix type systems. In case I forget why someday.
Dotfiles files in braille? are they for the blind?Dotfiles in Linux are hidden files preceded with a period. Depending on the program, they are used for configuration in your home directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitmproxy and Android</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitmproxy-and-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/mitmproxy-and-android/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Debugging network traffic for your app can be useful, and sometimes necessary if the data is not what is expected or inconsistent.
The Proxy I prefer the open source proxy [mitmproxy](https://mitmproxy.org =300x203). Easy to install on OSX with homebrew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fortunes on Slack</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/fortunes-microservice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/fortunes-microservice/</guid>
      <description>view the service homepage
Introduction Have always enjoyed the UNIX fortunes program, ever since I was a wee newbie. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with it (sad), yes, its like a fortune cookie.
It can be more technical in nature but not always.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir and Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/elixir-and-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/elixir-and-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you dont know phoenix framework, I&amp;rsquo;d describe it as rails for elixir. If you dont know Elixir I&amp;rsquo;d describe it as a functional language that feels like ruby for erlang.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know erlang it has been around a while (open-sourced in 1998) and the virtual machine is designed to be highly fault tolerant and scalable for use in telecoms, banking and instant messaging (WhatsApp).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Programming Quotes</title>
      <link>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/best-programming-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/posts/best-programming-quotes/</guid>
      <description>Quotes that relate to software engineering always humble me with their laser-like honesty. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep a collection of my favorites here (in no particular order).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
