<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on ryan jennings</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/post/musings/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on ryan jennings</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanjennin.gs/post/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Questioning the Queue</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/12/15/questioning-the-queue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/12/15/questioning-the-queue/</guid><description>Do you feel entitled to be a victim of someone or something else?
Do you think you mind or the situation generates more suffering?
That you deserve better? That you are overlooked?
That your perception of reality is absolute?
That you might physically die if you are not what you believe?
Do people take advantage of your suffering? Or challenge it?
Is your suffering physical, mental or both?
Do you think there is a &amp;ldquo;mind behind the mind&amp;rdquo; that sees with pureness (awareness)?</description></item><item><title>Mornin 'Mericas.</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/21/mornin-mericas./</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/21/mornin-mericas./</guid><description>Winners and Losers. All of us have probably felt this is true in some level.
Its true with men, and the various games in the lives of the different hues of man.
Have not read Trumpian literature on the subject but do have my own opinion that is somewhat biased to the loser side.
Starting with the most noisy:
Winners In the winner realm there are other dualities that signify their deserving of winning.</description></item><item><title>Covac</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/09/covac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/11/09/covac/</guid><description>Am very glad a covid vaccine has a real chance.
&amp;ldquo;Little bottle of hope&amp;rdquo; for saving humans and creating prosperity for more.
That being said, I am actually very bitter going back to the new-normal, with a lot of skepticism.
Seed of the Lemon The root of my problem is that the new-normal is just the old-abnormal and that pre-covid life was not that great anyway.
We were always already living on the edge of collapse: environmental, economic, war, societal, or technological.</description></item><item><title>The Dreams</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/31/the-dreams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/31/the-dreams/</guid><description>Life is a like a dream, a background awareness of reality.…. as a nightmare at worst and a delusion at best. You can guide your self down the stream, but you do not know where you are going and you cannot go back.
Caught somewhere in between the trickle of survival, getting ahead, a social life, and a personal life - the dream of solid ground seems a myth.</description></item><item><title>Poly Techs</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/18/poly-techs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/18/poly-techs/</guid><description>Politics. Does it matter? Why?
It is great that the human condition is suffering, as there is a plethora of issues to take unconscious action on.
When it comes down to actionable issues that are most common, it is always children.
Save the puppies first and foremost. It all kind of bubbles up to that.
Real change like saving the environment, technology, inequality, transcending the ego or peace always has an undesired effect that conflicts with the puppies.</description></item><item><title>Artist, Art tisk.</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/10/artist-art-tisk./</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/10/artist-art-tisk./</guid><description>The wikipedia on art in the 21st century is hilariously lacking.
Curious how distracted it all feels, rebounding in trauma from the constant suffering and crises.
There are some great artists who get overlooked compared to economics, disasters, in-equality or technology. The art itself is reflected by that merely resembles pornography or violence.
Art delivery has a digital / non-digital divide that correlates with the 21st century.
The first 20 years have been a digital revolution.</description></item><item><title>Indulgence into the past</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/01/indulgence-into-the-past/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/10/01/indulgence-into-the-past/</guid><description>Hello, World Trying to find at least zero motivation for the tech industry instead of negative infinity.
Do not normally focus too much on the past, in fact I tend to block out most of the bad parts.
But it might be worth investigating for a source redemption from the conditions that negate me.
But if you cannot be bothered to read more than 500 characters about someone else, here is the TL;DR:</description></item><item><title>The Dead Triplets</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/09/05/the-dead-triplets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/09/05/the-dead-triplets/</guid><description>This post could about music theory and rhythm, such as the triplet guitar riffs in invincible&amp;hellip;
But this about a single chapter, in a single book from the swamp. It is probably already a more influential book than I realize, from which I quote liberally and implicitly.
As monks say, the soul is wet (thus presumably messy) and a dry soul is lacking life.
entroducing&amp;hellip; Our society emphasizes the external [1]</description></item><item><title>Myths Fading, Direction of Evolution</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/07/07/myths-fading-direction-of-evolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2020/07/07/myths-fading-direction-of-evolution/</guid><description>Remembering a concept from the book Sapiens (paraphrasing):
Ape hierarchy only existed in small groups with a limit (150 or so) with a dominant leader (alpha). This applies to humans as well, but we were able so surpass the threshold with myths and better communication.
And the definition of ego by ET 👽:
A complete and total identification with form as who you are - a thought form or a physical form.</description></item><item><title>What I've Learned from 4 Years of Eckhart Tolle</title><link>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanjennin.gs/2019/01/12/what-ive-learned-from-4-years-of-eckhart-tolle/</guid><description>Major Lessons Eckhart Tolle or ET is a unique individual, author and orator. After a suicidal night where he thought &amp;ldquo;I cannot live with myself any longer&amp;rdquo; and recognized the oddity of thought, as if there were two people &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;myself&amp;rdquo;. That recognition brought a radical inner transformation and years of intense bliss. He later learned more about what happened to him and became a &amp;ldquo;spiritual teacher&amp;rdquo;.
His books The Power of Now and A New Earth have been #1 on the New York Times best seller list.</description></item></channel></rss>